# **Nitesh Singh**

+91 8154844112

itsnitesh01@gmail.com



,**9**, Surat, Gujarat

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nitesh-singh-647866239

https://niteshsingh-portfolio.netlify.app/

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

I'm a Skilled Front-end Developer experience in designing, developing and maintaining front-end web applications using React JS. I have experience in creating responsive and visually appealing websites and web applications with cross-browser compatibility and optimal performance.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

- Languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript.
- Libraries React JS, Redux Toolkit, jQuery, Ant Design.
- Frameworks Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Next JS.
- CI/CD Git
- Low Code No Code Tools Web Flow, Wix
- Code Analysis & Formatting Tools ESLint, Husky.

### **EXPERIENCE:**

## Front End Developer - The Complete Softech | Jan 2023 - May 2024

- Assisted the development team to develop multiple websites and web applications.
- Implemented front-end technical solutions to meet project requirements.
- Worked in an agile, collaborative environment to receive design requirements and test applications.
- Assisted QA team to find the design and responsive issues in WordPress plugins.

## Web Development and Designing Intern - Adept Digitals Pvt. Ltd. | Jul 2022 - Sep 2022

- Successfully performed multiple tasks that were assigned by the mentor.
- Learned how to work with a team in various projects and detailed worked as client's requirement.
- Research and development of multiple webpages and make clones of web pages with improvements.

## **PROJECTS:**

## Sabha Management Web App

Tech Stack - HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React JS, MUI Theme, MySQL, Redux Toolkit.

- Created a responsive user interface using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 5.0.1, MUI Theme.
- Created web pages with React JS functional component-based layout.
- API integration with web pages as required with seamless operations.
- Add/Edit User data inside MUI modal component.

# **Project Management Tool**

Tech Stack - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Webpack, Bootstrap, Chart.js, CK Editor.

- Front End Design using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap with interactive and Responsive user interface.
- Created web pages with React JS functional component-based layout.
- API integration with web pages for data management.
- Created dashboard page using different charts, tables and created custom chart for user's project timeline.
- Worked with the QA team, successfully resolved bugs and added improvement as needed.

#### **Exam Web App**

Tech Stack - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Bootstrap, MySQL.

- Data listing of faculties and subjects from API.
- Created MCQ exam page that used in multiple exams data such as (Mock test, Practice test etc)
- Created dashboard page of exam app that shows real time student progress, upcoming exams, greetings, and recommendations.

# **EDUCATION:**

K. J. Institute of Engineering and Technology | Bachelor of Engineering | Jul 2020 - May 2023 Government Polytechnic Gandhinagar | Diploma Engineering | Aug 2013 - Jun 2016